成社长不会有事吧？
Do you think Mr. Seong will be okay?
不会已经出事了吧？
What if they already did something to him?
如果想弄死他
就没必要带到这么远的地方了
They wouldn't have brought him this far
if they wanted to kill him.
他们带成社长去那个岛了吗？
进行游戏的那个岛？
Do you think they've taken him
to the island where they play the games?
目前还不确定 但很有可能
I'm not sure, but it seems likely.
我记得那个岛
就在这片海的某个地方 我确定
If I recall,
the island was somewhere in this area.
“如果我们活捉负责人失败
无论如何都要想办法潜入游戏岛”
"If we fail to capture the Front Man,
we infiltrate the island."
按照成社长制定的备用计划行动
That was Mr. Seong's plan B.
It's going according to plan.
游戏一旦开始
成奇勋说不定会有生命危险
Once the games begin,
Mr. Seong's life may be in danger.
必须尽快找到 免得为时已晚
We must find him before it's too late.
等我抓住那些混蛋
我非用电直接电死他们
If I catch those bastards,
I'm going to electrocute their asses.
来！
All right!
所有人都上船了 我们就出发吧！
If everyone's aboard, let's go!
（实时位置信息）
《鱿鱼游戏 2》
SQUID GAME 2
集名：《第三集 001》
EPISODE 3
456号
Player 456.
有太多东西放不下
没办法离开 也没办法止步
I sense you're holding on to many things.
You can't leave or stay.
拼命反抗也没用 你的命就是这样
You can't fight it. It's your destiny.
在九泉游荡的那些人的冤魂
在你脑中挥之不去
You have souls hovering over your head
who are lingering in this world.
你来这里不是你的意愿
是那些冤魂把你拉来的
You're not here of your own will.
Those vengeful souls brought you.
如果我们离开这里 来找我做个法事
If we get out of here,
let me perform a ritual.
我可以洗清你所有的报应
I can get rid of all your bad karma.
热烈欢迎各位来到这里
I would like to extend
a hearty welcome to all of you.
在接下来的六天中
各位都要参加六场不同的游戏
Everyone here will participate
in six different games over six days.
六个游戏全部通关的人
将获得巨额奖金
Those who win all six games
will receive a handsome cash prize.
请问！
Excuse me.
如果只是来玩游戏
这样把人绑架过来
You said I'd be playing games,
but you practically kidnapped me.
叫人怎么相信？
So how can I believe that?
不好意思 为了维护游戏的安全
I apologize.
Please understand that it was necessary
只能出此下策 希望各位理解
to maintain the game's security.
那你们戴面具做什么？
What's with the mask then?
大叔你的脸也是秘密吗？
Is your face also a secret?
对啊！为什么把脸遮起来？
Yeah! Why are you hiding your face?
这里是那种非法赌场之类的地方吗？
Is this some kind of
illegal gambling house?
就算在那种地方
发牌的人也不遮住脸啊！
Even the dealers don't cover their faces
in those places.
对 就是啊
为了确保游戏公平进行 维持保密性
To ensure fair gameplay
and confidentiality,
不公开工作人员的面孔和身份
始终是我们的原则
it is our policy not to reveal
the faces and identities of staff.
希望各位理解
Please understand.
是你们这些大叔把我衣服脱掉
给我换了这套吗？
Did you take off my clothes
and put these on me?
这鞋是怎么回事？
What's with these shoes?
我的鞋子是限量版的
My shoes are limited fucking edition.
很难找的！
They're hard to find!
如果我那双鞋毁了 你们要负责吗？
You going to replace them
if they get ruined?
这衣服尺寸也不合适 颜色也这么丑
These don't fit and the color sucks.
你们穿的那衣服 给我一件不行吗？
Can I just have
what you're wearing instead?
我喜欢粉色
I like pink.
很抱歉 不可以
I'm sorry, but that is not possible.
为了游戏的进行 请穿着统一服装
You must be in your uniforms
for the games.
我的手机呢…
What about my phone?
我的手机和钱包
为什么被拿走了？请还给我
Why did you take my phone and wallet?
Give them back, please.
各位的随身物品 我们会好好保管
We're keeping your belongings safe.
游戏结束后 会全部还给你们
We'll return them once the games are over.
那至少把手机还给我
我需要看加密货币价格走势
At least give me my phone.
I need to check the crypto market.
如果没有及时卖掉赔了钱
你们会负责吗？
If I lose money, will you compensate me?
游戏结束后会还给你
We will return it to you
once the games are over.
我要观看实时价格！
I need to monitor the real-time prices!
知道我在里面投资了多少钱吗？
Do you know how much I've invested?
333号 李明基
Player 333, Lee Myung-gi.
年龄30岁 YouTube“MG币”频道博主
Age 30, used to run a YouTube channel
called MG Coin.
在频道中诱导订阅观众投资一种
叫做达尔马提亚的新加密货币
After convincing subscribers to invest
in a new crypto coin called Dalmatian,
造成损失约152亿韩元
causing losses
of approximately 15.2 billion won,
将频道关闭后失踪
you shut down and disappeared.
现因涉嫌诈骗
You're wanted for fraud
违反《通信保护法》
与《金融管理法》正在被通缉
and for violating telecom
and financial investment laws.
李明基本人
目前在金融圈负债18亿韩元
Current debt levels, 1.8 billion won.
196号 姜敏雅 债务4500万
Player 196, Kang Mi-na,
45 million won in debt.
120号 赵贤珠 债务三亿三千万
Player 120, Cho Hyun-ju,
330 million won in debt.
230号 崔秀峰 债务11.9亿
Player 230, Choi Su-bong,
1.19 billion won in debt.
198号 张道英 债务14亿
Player 198, Jang do-yeong,
1.4 billion won in debt.
226号 金英参 债务19亿
Player 226, Kim Yeong-sam,
1.9 billion won in debt.
444号 金南度 20.2亿
Player 444, Kim Nam-du,
2.02 billion won in debt.
343号 沈在锡 28.9亿
Player 343, Sim Jae-seok,
2.89 billion won in debt.
006号 朴美华 31亿
Player 006, Park Mi-hwa,
3.1 billion won in debt.
283号 李允珠 40.2亿
Player 283, Lee Eun-ju,
4.02 billion won in debt.
100号 林正大
Player 100, Im Jeong-dae,
债务100亿
ten billion won in debt.
再来一局！
One more game!
100亿？谁啊？
Ten billion? Who's that?
谁啊？
Who is it?
看什么看？
What are you looking at?
借到100亿 你们以为容易吗？
Do you think it's easy
to get a ten-billion-won loan?
不是谁都能借到100亿的！
They don't lend
that kind of money to just anyone!
有那个能力偿还 才能借出来
Only to those
who are capable of paying it back.
现在在场的各位
All of you in this room
全都负债累累 无力偿还
have crippling debts
处在生活的悬崖边缘
and are now on a cliff-edge.
我们第一次去找各位的时候
各位也不相信我们
When we first came to you,
you did not trust us either.
但如你们所见 我们玩一个游戏
But as you know, we played a game
就能兑现承诺 给你们钱
and gave you money as promised.
各位相信了我们
And so you trusted us
全部都是自愿参加本游戏
不带有任何强制成分
and volunteered to participate
according to your own free will.
现在再给各位重新选择一次的机会
You have one last chance to decide.
各位是要回去
余生都被债主追 像垃圾一样生活？
Do you want to live like a piece of trash,
running from creditors?
还是会抓住我们提供的最后机会？
Or will you seize
the last opportunity we are offering?
正在靠近
Getting closer.
应该是去前面的其中一个岛
I think it's one of those islands ahead.
船长 请加速
Captain, let's pick up the speed.
是 遵命
Sure, as you wish.
各位现在看到的
What you see now
是存放各位宝贵奖金的小猪存钱罐
is the piggy bank where
your valuable prize money will be stored.
各位在进行全部六个游戏的过程中
每结束一个游戏
After each of the six games you will play,
这个小猪存钱罐里就会有奖金累积
the prize money will accumulate
in this piggy bank.
奖金能有多少？
How much is the prize money?
本次游戏的奖金总计456亿
The prize money for the games
is 45.6 billion won in total.
456亿？
45.6 billion won?
由一个人全部带走吗？
And one of us will get it?
奖金分配的具体事宜
We will give you the details
将在第一个游戏结束后告知各位
about the distribution of the prize money
after the first game.
在本次游戏中 各位将得到
一个从前游戏中没有的优势
For these games,
you will be given a special new advantage.
那是什么？
What is it?
每场游戏结束后 你们将得到
After each game,
you will be given a chance
通过投票
决定游戏继续还是终止的机会
to vote on whether
to continue the games or not.
如果希望终止游戏的人更多
If the majority votes to stop the games,
游戏将会终止 各位可以带着
截至那个时候积累的奖金离开
you can leave with the prize money
accumulated up to that point.
你是说
Are you saying
就算玩完一个游戏就离开
也能得到奖金吗？
we'll still receive the money,
even if we leave after the first game?
没错
That is correct.
哎呀 你这家伙！让一下 稍微让一下
Good heavens. Excuse me.
喂 你这臭小子！
You idiot!
妈！你怎么来了？
Mom! What… What are you doing here?
我还想问你呢！你来这里干什么？
That's what I wanted to ask you!
What are you doing here?
你干什么？怪丢脸的
You're embarrassing me.
丢脸？
Embarrassing?
你要是知道丢脸 还能来这里？
If you knew what was embarrassing,
you wouldn't be here!
你别说了！我们以后单独说
Stop it! We'll talk about this later.
哪里来的以后单独说
你快点走 赶快离开这里
No, we won't. Come on, you're leaving.
赶紧从这里出去 嗯？
You're leaving now, okay?
妈 你为什么来这里？
Mom, why did you come here?
你一个老太太 跟来干吗？
知道这是什么地方吗？都不害怕！
Do you realize where you are?
This is no place for an old lady!
我为什么来？嗯？
Why did I come here?
为了给你还债才来的 臭小子！
你是真不知道才问的吗？
To pay off your debt, of course!
Do you even have to ask?
你这个混蛋小子
You fool.
一个什么都不懂的老太太
为什么要把她弄来这里？
Why would you bring
a naive old woman here?
万一我妈妈在这里晕倒了
你们要负责吗？
Will you take responsibility
if my mom collapses?
容植 我留下来玩游戏
Yong-sik, I'll stay and do this.
你就回家吧 嗯？
You go home.
妈！我都已经来了
怎么能就这样回去？
Stop it! I'm already here.
I can't just leave.
你答应过我的 嗯？
But you promised me.
以后都不再赌博了 嗯？
You promised never to gamble again!
不是 这不是赌博 只是在玩游戏
No, this isn't gambling.
We're just playing games here.
我只要玩一局游戏就走 嗯？
I'll just play one game and go.
你个混蛋小子 玩游戏
这就是赌博游戏
You idiot, it's the same thing.
- 你别闹了！
- 臭小子
- Be quiet! That's enough!
- Don't you dare.
- 你这像话吗？
- 这是游戏 对吧 各位？是游戏吧？
- Are you kidding me?
- They're just games! Right, everyone?
想参加游戏的人
请在玩家同意书下方签字
If you wish to participate in the games,
please sign the player consent form.
不想参加游戏的人 请现在告知
Those who do not wish to participate,
please speak up now.
我们总会给各位退出游戏的机会
We always give you a chance
to leave the games.
真的只玩一个游戏
就能给我们钱 对吧？
You'll really pay us
even if we play just one game?
妈 你玩什么游戏？你赶快走吧！
Mom, you can't play any games.
Just go home!
喂 你不走 我就不走
If you're not leaving, neither am I.
- 我要在这里 跟你一起离开
- 快点吧
- I'm not going anywhere without you.
- Will you hurry up?
MG币的绝技明基 是吗？
The amazing Myung-gi from MG Coin?
Is that you?
请问您是哪位？
Who are you?
你可能不认识我 但我认识你 MG币
You may not know me, but I know you.
MG Coin.
我订阅了你的频道
I was subscribed to your channel.
我因为你损失了几个亿 你个混蛋
And I lost a shitload of money, asshole.
我也是
So did I.
你们认错人了
You've got the wrong person.
我白天晚上都看你的视频
I watched your content all day, every day.
梦里都全是你 你个王八蛋
Now I even see you in my dreams,
motherfucker.
- 你叫南秀吗？
- 南圭
- Was your name Nam-su?
- It's Nam-gyu.
- 五角俱乐部总经理
- 啊 对
- From Club Pentagon.
- Right.
因为你 我在这里
和南奎很快关系就变亲了
Thanks to you,
I bonded quickly with Nam-gyu here.
因为我们有共同的痛苦
Because we shared the same pain.
创造那个币的那些王八蛋带着钱
I thought the sons of bitches
who made that coin
不是逃到菲律宾去了吗？
fled to the Philippines with the money.
你怎么在这里？他们把你抛弃了吗？
So why are you here?
Did they cut you loose?
那您想怎么样？
What do you want from me?
你说怎么样？还钱呗
What do you think? Give me my money.
我强迫你们买那个币了吗？
Did I force you to buy that coin?
不是你这个王八蛋
叫我们有多少钱 全投进去吗？
You told us to bet it all, you fucker.
不是说一定会涨吗？
You swore it'd shoot up.
不是说 不买就是白痴吗？
你这个混蛋！
You said we'd be fucking idiots
if we didn't buy it!
“对投资最终决定的判断
和责任在于本人”
"You are responsible for
the final decision on your investment."
这是我在最后一个视频里说的
您没听到吗？
Didn't you hear me say that at the end?
您不是说自己是粉丝吗？
You said you watched every day.
- 哎呀 大哥 忍一忍！
- 王八蛋
- Hey, calm down!
- You asshole.
- 行了！
- 你干什么？放开
- All right now!
- Get off me.
放开我
Let go of me.
这么多人看着呢
People are watching.
打人就变成新闻了
You don't want to be on the news.
你最好在游戏里好好表现
结束之后我过来收钱
You'd better do well
because I'm coming to get my money back.
走吧
Come on.
（参加同意书）
PLAYER CONSENT FORM
（1. 不允许玩家擅自退出游戏）
1. A PLAYER IS NOT ALLOWED
TO VOLUNTARILY QUIT THE GAMES
（2. 拒绝游戏的玩家将被淘汰）
2. A PLAYER WHO REFUSES TO PLAY
WILL BE ELIMINATED
（3. 超过半数玩家同意
可终止游戏）
3. THE GAMES MAY BE TERMINATED
UPON A MAJORITY VOTE
（如果出现平局 再次投票）
IN CASE OF A TIE,
PLAYERS WILL VOTE AGAIN
（4. 如果游戏终止
其余玩家平分累积奖金）
4. IF THE GAMES ARE TERMINATED,
PLAYERS WILL DIVIDE THE PRIZE EQUALLY
（签名）
SIGNATURE
不想参加游戏的人
Those who do not wish to participate,
请现在告知
please speak up now.
（成奇勋）
SEONG GI-HUN
我就知道会是这样
你不是说放弃找那个岛了吗？
A man shouldn't go back on his word.
You said you were giving up.
对不起
I'm sorry.
情况紧急 我能联系到的船长只有您
It was urgent,
and you were the only person I could call.
你带了这么多黑衣人突然出现
You showed up out of the blue
with those men in black.
这是在搞什么？
What the hell is going on?
而且毕竟我是这艘船的船长
In case you've forgotten,
I'm the captain of this boat.
到底什么情况？你也给我讲讲
Tell me what the situation is.
我找到了关于那个岛位置的线索
I got a lead on where the island is.
什么线索？
And what is it?
我遇见参加过游戏的人了
I found someone who played the games.
- 真的吗？
- 对
- Really?
- Yes.
那个人又被带回那个岛了
But it looks like
he's been taken back there.
我们正在追踪他的位置
We're tracking his location.
黄刑警！
Detective Hwang!
我看好像是那边的那个岛！
My device is telling me
it's that island over there!
您知道那个岛吗？
Are you familiar with it?
嗯 那个岛以前有人生活
Yeah, people used to live there.
现在只有海钓的人偶尔去
Nowadays, people just go there to fish
from time to time.
大概就是那个地方了吧？
It seems like it may be the right place.
如果是那座岛 应该有车走的路
If it is, there should be
roads for vehicles
还有直升机停机坪之类的设施
and facilities like a helicopter pad.
我放无人机过去找找
I'll fly the drone over and see.
崔理事下船之后
找找信号所在的地方
You should go ashore
and follow the tracker.
好 听好了！准备着陆！
Okay. Listen up! Get ready to disembark!
稍后将开始第一个游戏
The first game will begin momentarily.
微笑
Smile.
玩家拍照完毕后
After having your picture taken,
请依照工作人员的指示走到游戏场
follow the staff's instructions
and proceed to the game site.
您是说唱歌手萨诺斯吧？
You're Thanos, the rapper.
我去了
Oh, shit.
请看镜头
Please look into the camera.
“用我的说唱杀掉一半的人类 砰”
I'm gonna kill half of humanity
With my raps, bam
《说唱战场》决赛亚军
The runner-up
of The Rap Battleground final.
哥 我叫京秀 是你的粉丝
我去过你的演唱会很多次
I'm Gyeong-su, big fan.
I've been to several of your concerts.
哥 可以跟我拍一张合影吗？
Please take a picture with me.
- 也跟我拍一张吧！
- 我也要拍一张！
- Me too!
哎 等一下！
Hang on, guys!
我们萨诺斯大哥有点累了
所有人一起拍一张吧
Let's make this easier on Thanos
and take one picture together.
怎么样 哥 可以吗？
Would that be okay?
- 来 大家聚一聚
- 是萨诺斯！
- All right, let's get together.
- It's Thanos!
喂 那边的也可以一起拍 过来吧
Hey, I don't mind
having one more person. Come on.
微笑
Smile.
大家的脸都要入镜哦
Are we all in the shot?
不能这样
You are not allowed to do this.
你也想一起拍吗？来吧
You want to be in the picture? Come on.
照片一次只能拍一个人
You must take your photos one by one.
哎呀 就这样拍一张不行吗？
Come on, can't you make an exception?
你们把手机收走了
没办法拍照了 好吗？
You took our phones,
and we can't take any pictures.
不可以
No.
等我们从这里出去 拿到了手机
我跟你们一个一个单独合影
When we get out of here,
I'll take a picture with each of you.
- 真的吗？我去 太好了！
- 先散开吧
- Okay. Guys, let's go.
- All right! Sweet!
请看镜头
Please look into the camera.
微笑
Smile.
那个是男的还是女的？
Is that a man or a woman?
就是有这样的人
There are people like that.
本来是男人 但是想成为女人
They're men who want to be women.
- 男人为什么想成为女人？
- 嘘
Why would they want to be women?
男人就是男人 女人就是女人
Men are men, and women are women.
现在可不能说这样的话
You can't say things like that.
- 嘘 走吧
- 哎哟 没眼看
Good grief, that's unsightly.
请看镜头
Please look into the camera.
微笑
Smile.
怎么了？
What?
奇勋！
Gi-hun!
正倍
Jung-bae.
喂！你小子活着呢？
Fuck, you were alive this whole time?
你怎么来了？
What are you doing here?
什么我怎么来了？那你怎么来了？
What am I doing here?
What are you doing here?
你小子 已经三年没有你的消息了
听说你妈妈去世了
No one's heard from you for three years.
I heard your mom passed away.
这种消息
非要我从老婆那里听到吗？
I had to hear about it from my wife!
你算什么朋友？怎么不跟我说一声？
What kind of friend are you?
因为我以前没借给你钱
你就跟我断绝联系了吗？
Were you going to cut me out
because I didn't lend you money?
往前走走 别挡路！
Keep moving! Don't block the way.
不是那样的
It's not like that.
有点特殊情况
It's a long story.
是啊 既然你也来了这里
不用你说 也能大概知道
Right. I can imagine,
seeing as you're here.
但是你也太过分了
你妈去世了 应该告诉我啊
Still, you should've told me
about your mom.
你妈妈那么喜欢我
You know how much she liked me.
你来这里干什么？
Why are you here?
弟媳怎么办？
What about your wife?
离婚了
We got divorced.
离婚？
Divorced?
孩子呢？
What about your kid?
妈妈带走了
With my wife.
为什么？你们感情不是很好吗？
Why? I thought you guys were doing okay.
你有外遇了？
Did you have an affair?
你看我像能有外遇嘛？
Yeah, like I could manage one.
别在这里说了
Let's not talk about it here.
游戏结束之后
出去一起喝一杯 聊聊这些
When we get out,
let's go for a drink and talk.
正倍 现在开始
一定要紧紧跟在我身后
Jung-bae. Whatever happens from now on,
stay close to me.
都不见我了 突然这么肉麻
紧紧跟着你干吗？小子
"Stay close"? You've gotten melodramatic.
一定要听我的话！
Just do as I say!
一定要紧紧跟在我身后！
You must stay close behind me!
行了 知道了
All right, man. I will.
怎么还突然玩上火车游戏了 嗯？
Like this? Like Follow the Leader?
喂 不过这个地方的结构
怎么弄得这么复杂？
By the way, this is crazy.
What is this place?
（实时位置信息）
是这边！
This way!
从小岛周边开始 低调一点
Start from the coast. Keep it low.
是
Got it.
哎哟
Damn.
- 欢迎各位来到第一项游戏
- 怎么这么多楼梯？腿好痛！
- Welcome to the first game.
- My legs! That was a lot of stairs.
请各位玩家先在运动场上等待
All players,
please wait a moment on the field.
重复一遍
Let me repeat.
请各位玩家
All players,
- 先在运动场上等待
- 喂 小姐
- please wait a moment on the field.
- Hey, señorita.
你不认识我吗？
Don't you know who I am?
应该认识吗？
Do I have to?
不认识也没关系
No, you don't.
现在开始认识就行了
你住哪里？几岁了？
We can get to know each other.
Tell me about yourself.
你在撩我吗？
Are you hitting on me?
人山人海中 你立刻吸引了我的眼球
In the sea of faces, you caught my eye
一片杂草中盛开的 我的美丽花朵
My beauty, my flower blooming among weeds
红、橙、黄、绿 我是传奇萨诺斯
Red, orange, yellow, green
I'm a legend, Thanos
看看我们这蓝绿色衣服
Look at us in this blue-green
拜托给我开绿灯
Now give me the green light
我喜欢你
I like you!
那是什么东西？
What's that?
What's that thing?
可恶 这不是给人走的路啊
Damn, this isn't built for us to walk on.
找到了 那里！
I found him! Over there!
第一个游戏是“一二三 木头人”
The first game is Red Light, Green Light.
- 她说“一二三 木头人”吗？
- 你看吧？
- We're playing Red Light, Green Light?
- See?
- 不是赌博 是游戏
- 小孩玩的游戏啊
We're playing games, not gambling.
This is a children's game.
“一二三 木头人”？小时候玩那种？
Red Light, Green Light? The kids' game?
大叔
Hey, you.
您说我吗？
Me?
您在干什么？
What… What are you doing?
- 可恶
- 您这是干什么？
- Damn it.
- Hey, what are you doing?
- 老实一点 不要动
- 你们这是干什么？
- Freeze. Don't move.
- Who the hell are you?
别动
Do not move.
你干什么呢？怎么了？
What are you doing?
你把种植牙拔了吗？
Is that your dental implant?
在哪里？
Where is it?
妈的
Damn it.
死定了
I'm fucked.
- 这是从哪里来的？
- 那是什么？
- Where did you get this?
- Get what?
这个为什么在你这里？
Why was this in here?
那个？是我刚才上船之前
That? Before I got on the boat here,
有人说是他剩的虫子
把这些送给我了 怎么了？
some guy said he had leftover bait
and gave that to me. Why?
黄刑警 完蛋了 被他们发现了
Detective Hwang, we're screwed.
They're onto us.
他们把追踪器
放在别人身上 送到了这里
They put the GPS tracker on someone else.
游戏准备完毕
We are ready to start the game.
开始
Start.
在五分钟之内
躲过鬼的侦查 跨越终点线的人…
Cross the finish line in five minutes
without getting caught.
- 就算过关
- 各位！
- If you do, you pass.
- Everyone!
各位 请看这里！注意这里！
Everyone, listen up! Pay attention!
现在开始仔细听我说的话！
Listen carefully!
这不是普通的游戏！
This is not just a game!
如果被侦测到移动
If you lose the game,
会死！
you die!
说什么呢？
What is he saying?
大叔 您在说什么啊？
Hey! What are you talking about?
玩着“一二三 木头人” 就死了？
We're going to die
playing Red Light, Green Light?
- 木头人！
- 对 没错！
- Red light…
- Yes, that's right!
如果被侦测到移动 就会死！
If they catch you moving,
they will kill you!
他们会从某个地方开枪射击！
They will shoot you from somewhere!
那位大叔喝酒了吧？
That guy must be drunk.
- 一定要格外小心！
- 他说如果我们被抓到会挨枪
- Stay on your toes!
- He says they'll shoot us if we lose.
像我们家老头子似的
He sounds like my old man
喝醉回家 刚到门口就开始胡言乱语
when he gets home drunk
and starts talking crazy.
- 被发现会死！
- 说他脑袋里有窃听装置
- Says there's a freaking bug in his head.
- If you get caught, you die!
前面那个娃娃的眼睛是动作侦测器！
That doll's eyes are motion detectors!
- 你看他 说什么侦测器
- 被侦测到就死了！
- See? Talking about devices.
- Stay on your toes!
被侦测到就要去见爸爸了？
We might get to join Dad today.
说什么鬼话呢？
What the hell are you talking about?
那个人应该是故意吓我们
想自己独吞奖金
I think he's trying to scare us
so he can win the prize money.
没错！
That's right!
别耍花样 混蛋！
Don't pull any tricks, asshole!
你们一定要相信我的话！
You have to believe me!
绝对不要害怕、恐慌！
Do not be alarmed or panic!
不管发生什么事 都不要惊慌乱跑！
No matter what happens,
do not panic and start running!
那么游戏现在开始
Let the game begin.
一二三 木头人
Green light, red light.
不要动！
Freeze!
做得好！只要保持冷静就可以了！
Well done!
You just need to stay calm like this!
只要在正确的时间移动
及时停止动作
We just have to move
and stop at the right time.
- 他怎么回事？
- 我们全都能活下来
- What's with him?
- Then we can all win.
- 通过这一关！
- 您认识他？
- We can survive together!
- Do you know him?
不认识
No, I don't.
一二三 木头人
Green light, red light.
不要动！
Freeze!
一动都不要动！
Don't move and stay still!
不要紧张！
Just relax!
别说了 你这样我更害怕了！
Cut it out. It's you that's scaring me!
要闭嘴说话 危险
Speak with your mouth covered.
It's dangerous.
一二三 木头人
Green light, red light.
- 你怎么不动？
- 不要动！
- Why aren't you moving?
- Freeze!
一二三 木头人
Green light, red light.
不要动！
Freeze!
- 你疯了吗？
- 我叫你捂住嘴！
- Are you crazy?
- I said cover your mouth!
- 一二三 木头人
- 跟我走！
- Green light, red light.
- Follow me!
不要动！
Freeze!
一二三 木头人
Green light, red light.
不要动！
Freeze!
一二三 木头人
Green light, red light.
不要动！
Freeze!
所有人一动都不要动！
Nobody move!
那个大叔是嗑药了吗？
Is he high or what?
没有 嗑药之后不是那样的
Nope.
No one is like that when they're high.
你试过？
You've been high?
你有兴趣？
You interested?
什么东西？
What's that?
它应该是知道你是花吧
你身上有只蜜蜂
He knows you're a flower.
There's a bee on you.
蜜蜂？
A bee?
我去 我动了
Crap.
I just moved.
全都不要动！
Nobody move!
绝对不能动一下！
You must not move!
196号 淘汰
Player 196, eliminated.
正倍 不管发生什么事 都不要动
Jung-bae.
No matter what happens, don't move.
千万不要动！
Do not move!
不行！不能动！
No! Don't move!
站在原地不要动！
Stay still!
如果逃跑 你会死！
If you run, you'll die!
你们要是动 就都死定了！
You will all die if you move!
不要！站在原地不要动！
Don't move! Keep yourselves still!
千万不要乱动！
Don't move, please!
不要动！
Freeze!
重复一遍
Let me repeat.
在鬼说“一二三 木头人”期间
可以前进
You can move forward while the tagger
shouts, "Green light, red light."
之后如果被侦测到移动
If your movement is detected afterward,
就会被淘汰
you will be eliminated.
一二三 木头人
Green light, red light.
时间到了 没走到的人也会死！
You'll also die
if you don't make it there in time!
那个娃娃是动作探测器！
That doll is a motion detector!
躲在后面侦测不到！
But it can't detect motion
that's not visible to it!
身形小的人躲在比你大的人后面！
Get behind someone bigger than you!
像玩小火车游戏那样
往前走就可以了！
Like you're doing Follow the Leader!
没时间了 现在必须快走！
We're running out of time!
We've got to move!
- 一二三 木头人
- 妈 过来 到我身后
- Get behind me.
- Green light, red light.
奇勋
Gi-hun.
现在开始 我紧紧跟在你身后
I'll stay close to you now.
188号
Player 188.
244号
Player 244.
一二三 木头人
Green light, red light.
不要动
Do not move.
你没事吧？紧贴在我身后
Are you okay?
Get close to me.
所有人不要动！
Do not move!
不要动！
Freeze!
什么鬼？
What the hell?
淘汰
Bye.
快走！
Let's go!
一二三 木头人…
Green light, red light…
我没动
It wasn't me.
- 是这个女的 她推了我 我没动！
- 444号
- She pushed me. I didn't move!
- Player 444.
是这个女的推我
It was her.
我没动
I didn't move.
444号 淘汰
Player 444, eliminated.
大家加油！马上就到了！
You can do this!
You're almost there!
一二三 木头人
Green light, red light.
救救我
Please help me.
- 一二三 木头人
- 喂！你去哪里？
- Green light, red light.
- Hey! Where are you going?
救救我
Please help me.
我帮你 下一个信号必须站起来
I'll help you. Get up on this turn.
一二三 木头人
Green light, red light.
一二三
Green…
木头
light…
人
red light.
你没事吧？
Are you okay?
谢谢
Thank you.
11号
Number 011.
是你吗？
Was that you?
我只是处理了一个淘汰的人
I simply took out a loser.
444号 淘汰
Player 444, eliminated.
完成任务的士兵们
请在狙击室前排队
Soldiers who have completed your mission,
please line up outside the sniper rooms.
喂 不要这样待着啊
We can't just sit here and do nothing.
附近的其他小岛
都应该找找看 不是吗？
We should at least search
some nearby islands.
他们把我们往这个方向诱导
就应该不在这附近
They led us here, so I don't think
they're anywhere in this area.
今天晚上有风浪预警
A storm warning
has been issued for tonight.
我们最好先回港口
We'd better head back to port.
该死
Damn it.
搜索可能要花上好一阵子
The search may take a while.
回去重新想个计划 再准备行动
We should go back
and come up with a new plan.
是谁走漏了消息？
Who leaked the information?
喂 是不是你们谁喝醉了酒
到处乱说了？
Did one of you get drunk
and blab about it somewhere?
走吧 天气又冷
也快黑天了 快点出发吧！
All right, it's getting cold and dark.
Let's get moving.
哥 你哪里不舒服吗？
You're not feeling well?
- 别担心
- 啊？
- Don't worry.
- What?
我没事
I'm okay.
喂 奇勋 那个长得
像疯女人的娃娃是什么鬼？
Gi-hun. What the hell is that creepy doll?
还能用眼睛开枪
It shoots people with its eyes.
不是娃娃开的枪
It's not the doll.
有枪手在别的地方
There are shooters.
你怎么知道这么多？
你真的以前来过这里吗？
How do you know so much?
Have you really been here before?
恭喜各位通过第一个游戏
Congratulations for making it
through the first game.
那么现在公布第一个游戏的结果
Here are the results of the first game.
（参加人员）
456名玩家中 91名被淘汰
Out of 456 players,
91 players have been eliminated.
通过第一个游戏的玩家有365名
365 players have completed the first game.
再次恭喜各位通过第一个游戏
Congratulations again
for making it through the first game.
先生！饶了我们吧！
Sir! Please don't kill us!
求求你 饶了我们吧！
Please don't kill us. I beg you!
我儿子欠的钱 一直到我死之前
As for my son's debt,
我会不惜一切代价把钱还上！
I will do whatever it takes
to pay you back!
求求你们 饶了我们吧！
Please forgive us!
喂 干什么呢？你也快求求他们
Don't just stand there.
Beg for his forgiveness.
我真的错了 求求你们饶我一次
I'm sorry. Please forgive me.
- 我一定会赚钱还的！
- 各位好像误会了
- I promise I'll pay it back!
- There seems to be a misunderstanding.
饶了我们吧！
Please don't kill us!
- 请饶了我们吧！
- 饶了我们吧！
- Please don't kill us!
- Please spare us!
我们并没有要伤害各位
We are not trying to harm you.
我们是在给各位一个机会
We are presenting you with an opportunity.
同意书第三条！
Clause three of the consent form.
“超过一半的玩家同意
可以终止游戏”
"The games may be terminated
upon a majority vote."
对吧？
Correct?
没错
That is correct.
那现在立刻让我们投票
Then let us take a vote right now.
当然可以
Of course.
我们尊重各位的自由意愿决定
We respect your right
to freedom of choice.
那么在投票前
我来揭晓目前为止累积的奖金数额
But first, let me announce
the prize amount that's been accumulated.
第一局游戏被淘汰的有91人
The number of players
eliminated in the first game is 91.
因此积累了总计91亿韩元
Therefore, a total of 9.1 billion won
has been accumulated.
如果各位现在退出游戏
If you quit the games now, the 365 of you
91亿的奖金要在剩下的365人中平分
can equally divide the 9.1 billion won
各位带着自己的分成数额离开
and leave with your share.
那是多少？
How much is that?
每个玩家的分成是2493万1500韩元
Each person's share would be
24,931,500 won.
操 我们玩个游戏差点死了
就给我们2400万？
Fuck. We almost died,
and they're giving us 24 million?
说什么屁话呢 操
That's fucking bullshit.
两千万？
Twenty million?
不是说456亿吗！
You said 45.6 billion!
根据游戏规则
The rule is that
每淘汰一名玩家 奖金累积一亿韩元
a hundred million won will be accumulated
for each eliminated player.
如果进行下一场游戏 还有玩家淘汰
If you choose to play the next game
and more players get eliminated,
奖金数额会相应增加
the prize amount
will increase accordingly.
那么如果走到最后 奖金有多少？
How much will it be
if you survive until the end?
我已经说过了
As I already told you,
总共456名玩家 总奖金数额是
the total amount of prize money
for all 456 players
456亿
is 45.6 billion won.
通过全部六场游戏的玩家
Those who make it through all six games
可以平分总奖金456亿
will equally divide the 45.6 billion won.
所以如果只剩下一个人
456亿可以独吞？
So if you're the only one to survive,
you get 45.6 billion?
没错
That is correct.
456亿？哇！
45.6 billion? Wow!
下一个游戏结束后出来
还是可以投票退出 对吧？
So we can take a vote again
and decide to leave after the next game?
正如同意书上承诺的那样
As promised in the consent form,
各位可以在每场游戏结束后通过投票
you can take a vote after each game
决定带着当时积累的奖金离开
and decide to leave with the prize money
accumulated up to that point.
我们始终认为
各位玩家主动参与的意愿是最重要的
We always prioritize
your voluntary participation.
好 现在开始投票
Now, let's begin the vote.
如果想继续游戏 按圆圈键
If you wish to continue the games,
press the O button.
如果想终止游戏 按叉键
If you wish to end them,
press the X button.
投票将按照玩家号码的倒序进行
The vote will be held
in reverse order of your player numbers.
456号
Player 456.
这一切都毫无意义！
It's all pointless!
正如你们无法决定
什么时候来到这个世界上一样
You didn't decide
when to come into this world,
离开的时候 你们也无法决定
and you can't decide
when you leave it either.
你们何时何地死亡
When and where you die
出生的那一刻开始
天地神明就已经决定了
were already decided by the gods
the moment you were born.
不管怎么拼命挣扎 都绝对无法逃脱
No matter how hard you try,
you can never escape it.
投票完成的人
Once you finish voting,
请将徽章贴在右胸口
put the patch you are given
on the right side of your chest
站在与徽章一致的那一边
and stand on the side you have chosen.
454号
Player 454.
453号
Player 453.
390号
Player 390.
388号
Player 388.
380号
Player 380.
333号
Player 333.
332号
Player 332.
246号
Player 246.
230号
Player 230.
等一下 各位！等等！
Wait a minute, everyone! Wait!
不能再这样下去了
You can't do this.
清醒一点！你们还没明白吗？
Come to your senses!
Don't you see?
这不是普通的游戏
These aren't just any games.
继续玩下去 我们都会死！
We will all die if we keep playing!
我们必须马上离开这里
只要投票赢了 就可以离开这里！
We have to get out of here now.
With a majority vote, we can!
我们必须在这里停下！
We must stop here!
你以为你是谁啊？
Who do you think you are?
为什么从刚才开始
就一直怂恿所有人？
Why do you keep
egging people on like that?
游戏还没开始呢
就说他们会开枪 吓我们！
You scared us by saying they'd shoot us
before the game even began!
对啊！
That's right!
这个男的跑到我们面前 一直说会死
He was going on about how we'd die,
我因为他说那些话更紧张了
差点因为他死了！
and I almost did because I got so nervous!
但你是怎么知道他们会开枪的？
How did you know
they were going to shoot us?
你是他们的一员吗？
Are you one of them?
你是内部工作人员
假扮成玩家进来骗我们吗？
Are you conning us all
by pretending to be a player?
你这人怎么回事？
Who is this guy?
这个人是你们为了操纵我们
故意安插的眼线吧？
Did you plant him to mess with our heads?
大叔 你怎么能这么说话呢？
That's uncalled for.
多亏了这位朋友 我们才打起精神
没有被发现移动 这才活了下来！
We wouldn't have won the game
and survived if it weren't for him!
还有你！我刚才全都看到了
你在那里怕得要死 腿一直在抖
And you! I saw how scared you were.
Your legs were shaking.
你应该对他心存感激才对
怎么能觉得他是骗子！
You should thank him,
not treat him like a fraud!
你是谁啊 站出来替他说话？
你们俩是一伙的吗？
And who the hell are you?
Are you conspiring with him?
“你”？你几岁了？
Rude. How old are you?
我比你大怎么办 嗯？
Older than you. What are you going to do?
行了 别这样了
- Come on now.
- What?
各位
Please don't do this. Listen.
我和各位都是
None of us would be alive
如果不是这位先生 现在早都死了
if it weren't for this gentleman.
各位不要贪心了
So enough with the greed.
要认识到生命的可贵
Let's put our lives first
所有人离开这里吧 好吗？
and get out of this place! Okay?
- 离开这里！
- 我们全部离开这里！
- That's right!
- Let's all get out of here!
- 离开什么离开！继续游戏啊！
- 干什么要离开啊？
- Let's get out of here!
- No, we have to keep playing!
我以前参加过这些游戏！
I have played these games before!
我以前参加过！
I have done this before!
我从第一个游戏就知道
是因为我以前玩过 全都见过！
I knew about the first game
because I had played it before!
我三年前在这里玩过这些游戏！
I played the games here three years ago!
当时和我一起玩游戏的人
And everyone who was with me…
全部都死了！
died here!
- 真的全都死了吗？
- 真死了？
- They all died?
- All of them?
- 真的吗？不可能吧？
- 等一下
- Really? No way.
- Hold on.
他们全都死了
你是怎么一个人活下来的？
If they all died,
how did you survive alone?
你是自己一个人赢了吗？
Wait, are you saying
you were the sole winner?
没错
That's right.
我是当时的赢家
I was the final winner.
再继续游戏
If we continue the games,
这里的每一个人
every single person here,
都会像当时的那些人一样
just like all the people back then,
全部死亡
will die in the end.
放屁
Bullshit.
如果你是唯一的赢家
你应该赢了456亿
If you were the sole winner,
it means you won 45.6 billion won.
那你为什么又回来这里？
If you really did,
why would you come back here?
没错！他在骗人！
That's right! He's lying!
对 你少放屁！
Cut the crap!
他就是个疯子！
He's a total nutcase!
你这样的人能赢 我也能赢！
If someone like you can win, so can I!
如果你真的赢过 那就更好了
If you really won,
it actually works better for us.
你可以给我们一些提示
You can give us some tips
怎么玩能获胜
on how to beat these games.
没错！
That's right!
我们这里有人赢过
还有什么好担心的？
We have a previous winner with us,
so what do we have to worry about?
我们再来一局吧！
Come on, let's do this!
- 来玩吧！
- 玩吧！
- Come on!
- Yeah!
- 去赚钱吧！
- 玩吧！
- Let's make some money!
- Let's do this!
- 继续玩！
- 玩吧！
- Let's do it!
- Let's try!
去赚钱！
Let's make money!
我真的求你们了
我们必须马上出去！
Please, I'm begging you.
We have to get out now!
继续玩下去 会死更多的人
If we keep playing, more people will die.
死的也有可能是您啊
That could be you.
立刻停止游戏 离开这里吧！
We have to stop this now
and get out of here.
各位
Everyone.
从现在开始 我们不会容忍
任何妨碍投票的行为
From here on, we will not tolerate actions
that disrupt the voting process.
那么现在继续投票
Now, let's resume the vote.
228号
Player 228.
100号
Player 100.
007号
Player 007.
容植 你！
Yong-sik!
不要有荒唐的想法 嗯？
Don't get any stupid ideas.
- 做得好！
- 好样的
That's right!
006号
Player 006.
004号
Player 004.
最后是001号
Lastly, Player 001.
来 大家一起说“圆圈”！
Everyone, say O!
- 圆圈！
- 叉！
- O!
- X!
字幕翻译：李江珊
Subtitle translation by: Yoonjung Song